<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Not a Blog</title>
    <atom:link href="https://nadyanay.me/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
    <link>https://nadyanay.me/blog</link>
    <description>A place to store my thoughts and write about things.</description>
    <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <generator>Wintersmith - https://github.com/jnordberg/wintersmith</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>I knew how to write once...</title>
      <link>https://nadyanay.me/blog/blog/articles/2024-02-November/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://nadyanay.me/blog/blog/articles/2024-02-November/</guid>
      <author>Nadya Nayme</author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Writing appears to be a talent that I have lost after decades of neglect. I was once an administrator for a forum of writers - what happened?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve always had a fond spot for writing from a young age. In fact, I owe my love of writing for my entire career in programming. You see when I was 9 years old I joined a forum, “Future Writers”. A hodge-podge of young adults and teenagers who shared a love of writing. The second youngest person I knew from the site was a teenage girl from the Netherlands, Hannah, who was 14 at the time. In fact in the mailbox of my first ever email address, one that my mother had helped me create, I still have an email from her with a poem that she wrote. Way back in the before times of 2007.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://nadyanay.me/blog/articles/2024-02-November/images/miss-you.png&quot; alt=&quot;Miss You by Hannah / XxWaterVampire17xX&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t worry, like nearly all of my contacts from 2007, her mailbox no longer exists. In the infinitesimal chance that someone reading this might know Hannah please tell her to email me I’d love to reconnect and chat how our lives have gone these past 17 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where was I again? Right. So here I am at 9 years old on a forum full of aspiring writers. Reading all sorts of edgy Tumblr-esque poetry and writings and sharing some of my own. I still have a written copy of one of my short stories titled “Flatline”. It’s about two young lovers who are so close that they were said to share a heartbeat. They have a short highschool fling and life drifts apart. The story is told from the man’s perspective with his heartbeat growing ever more frantic as he searches for her in their small town. The reason he is searching for her is because he felt his heartbeat quickening and realized she was having a heart attack and he wanted to see her once more. He never does find her as her heart begins to slow and then finally flatlines as she passes away. At that same moment, he collapses forward in the street and dies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A bit edgy? Sure. The above is but a short summary and not the actual story, which is about 2 pages long. Having read it back to myself some time in my adulthood I was rather impressed with 11 year old me at coming up with the concept but also writing a remarkably realistic highschool fling and how life often finds a way to separate young couples and the pain some of those couples carry with them at a love that might have been.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile I can hardly write 3 coherent paragraphs for this blog. What happened? Well I think it is mostly that I had stopped writing for nearly 20 years. That is certainly a cause of why one’s skills might diminish. So I wish to write once again. Whether it is about banal things, rants, short thoughts, where I belong in the world. Whatever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also need to start reading again. I would read often as a child and as an adult I tell myself I give myself the self-fulfilling prophecy of not having enough time or attention to read. Because I don’t set aside time or dedicate my attention to reading. The way to becoming a better writer involves an awful lot of reading - and while I do still read constantly I am not reading the type of materials that would help me become a better writer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I write mostly for myself but it would be nice to engage with an audience one day. Although I cant expect anyone to ever read or engage with my blog when my writing leaves quite a bit to be desired. It would do me good if I could organize my thoughts to be coherent and well-structured. So that is what I want to do.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Get Away From Gandi</title>
      <link>https://nadyanay.me/blog/blog/articles/2024-22-October/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://nadyanay.me/blog/blog/articles/2024-22-October/</guid>
      <author>Nadya Nayme</author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When leadership changes, enshittification is sure to follow. Especially if the company is a profitable company with an otherwise good reputation. The new owners will do everything they can to ruin it in an attempt to squeeze short-term profits. Gandi is now in competition with GoDaddy for being the worst possible registrar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On October 17th I received an email from Gandi. My domain, the one you are reading this from right now, was renewed. A typical annual event for me. I thought nothing of it at the time. Later that night I had a look at my account balance, by chance mostly, as I do not routinely check it. That’s when I saw this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://nadyanay.me/blog/articles/2024-22-October/images/renewal.png&quot; alt=&quot;$55 Domain Renewal&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$55 for a domain renewal? My domain isn’t worth that much! I hardly get any traffic on it and the TLD renewal fee is about $15/yr. For years Gandi has been about $17-$19/yr to renew (I forget the specifi camount if I am being honest). But first, we need to go back a little further… back to February 2023 when Gandi was acquired by Total Webhosting Solutions. I learned about this from &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=35080777&quot;&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt; and though to myself: “Well, that sucks. I’ll probably end up having to move registrars at some point.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the purchase they removed their free email service - which I refuse to pay someone $5/mo for. I spitefully moved my email to self-host using &lt;a href=&quot;https://mailinabox.email/&quot;&gt;Mail-in-a-Box&lt;/a&gt;. It still costs me $5/mo but I also get unlimited mailboxes and mailbox aliasing without having to pay for it. They also raised domain renewals by about 20% making them about the same price as more expensive registrars like GoDaddy and Namecheap. $22/yr renewal? A few dollars more than I was spending but not worth the hassle of moving away since other registrars charged about the same amount as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which brings me back to $55.98 for a domain renewal. That is more than &lt;strong&gt;double&lt;/strong&gt; and is in fact closer to &lt;strong&gt;triple&lt;/strong&gt; what it should cost. They apparently announced this further increase at some point but I never saw the email for it before it was too late - automatic renewals cannot be refunded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have another domain with Gandi - so I thought how much are they going to charge me to renew &lt;a href=&quot;https://aishitei.ru&quot;&gt;aishitei.ru&lt;/a&gt; in May of next year? Turns out - another $54! What the &lt;strong&gt;FUCK&lt;/strong&gt; Gandi‽ No. Absolutely not. Not paying that. I will move the heavens and do whatever I have to do to get the fuck away from Gandi at this point. I am not going to go from spending about $34&lt;del&gt;/yr on my domain renewals to $110&lt;/del&gt;/yr.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One issue though - Russia is at war with Ukraine. As a result many of the registrars I wanted to move to had stopped supporting domains using the &lt;code&gt;.ru&lt;/code&gt; TLD. So I couldn’t use &lt;a href=&quot;https://porkbun.com/&quot;&gt;Porkbun&lt;/a&gt; which seems to be an up-and-coming “No bullshit” registrar. I ended up finding a registrar that supports &lt;code&gt;.ru&lt;/code&gt; TLD and had a seemingly neutral reputation. So that domain has been moved to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netim.com/en&quot;&gt;Netim&lt;/a&gt;, which happens to be another France-based registrar. My new renewal fee? $13 - and it was even free to transfer the domain to Netim! Transfering a domain typically has a cost associated to it (usually the renewal fee or slightly cheaper) so that was nice to see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a small  headache with RU-Center to get my NIC-REG updated from Gandi to Netim the transfer was complete. Netim is now responsible for my &lt;code&gt;aishtiei.ru&lt;/code&gt; domain and, thankfully, I didn’t take my email down in the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://nadyanay.me/blog/articles/2024-22-October/images/netim.png&quot; alt=&quot;Netim announcing the succesful domain transfer of aishitei.ru&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next up was getting &lt;code&gt;nadyanay.me&lt;/code&gt; moved. While I could have moved it to RU-Center I have personal reasons for not wishing to do so. &lt;code&gt;.me&lt;/code&gt; has better support than a lot of registrars. I think my original plans were to go with Porkbun for this domain - but I ended up going with Cloudflare since they do renewals at-cost. While I do not support Cloudflare controlling what seems to be over half of the internet - I don’t expect them to rugpull me like Gandi did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://nadyanay.me/blog/articles/2024-22-October/images/cloudflare.png&quot; alt=&quot;Cloudflare announcing the succesful domain transfer of nadyanay.me&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gandi could have continued making $34/yr from me for the rest of my life. Now they get $0/yr and what used to be my top recommendation for people looking to purchase a domain is now a warning to “avoid at all costs”. They will never see another penny from me - either directly or indirectly. Their entire business strategy now is hoping people are either too lazy or lack the knowledge to move to another domain registrar. Don’t be one of those people! Jump ship and save yourself the money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn’t write this blog only to vent. I wrote this blog on the off-chance it will help prevent someone else from signing up at Gandi and as a warning to my future self and others: if a company you trust is ever sold, be ready to abandon ship sooner than later. I knew the enshittification would happen eventually. What I didn’t know was that it would happen as quickly as it did.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Worst It Will Ever Be</title>
      <link>https://nadyanay.me/blog/blog/articles/2024-19-September/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://nadyanay.me/blog/blog/articles/2024-19-September/</guid>
      <author>Nadya Nayme</author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been following deep learning and AI-generated media for nearly a deacde. Five years ago if you had asked me we would have an AI capable of generating hyper realistic videos of almost anything I would have called you crazy and told you we were still decades away from being able to pull that off…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ten years ago deep learning was all the rage. Five years ago AI videos still created things of nightmares. Colors mismatched and vague shapes bleeding through whatever you could call its creation. They seemed like videos you’d see someone make to simulate the experience of an LSD trip gone bad and the vision receptors of your brain being fried. This was cutting edge technology at the time. It was also the worst it would ever be. Shortly after that we applied face-recognition technology to create deepfakes by processing a face frame-by-frame to swap it with another face. You’d need a good enough GPU to pull it off and it would take a long time to get a passable result. Deepfakes began being used for so much porn that Reddit eventually banned the deepfake subreddit. That did nothing to halt the inevitable progress that was to come. As we learned better ways to develop neural networks and better ways to train them (GANs) progress seemed to go from a breakthrough here or there to a spike of breakthroughs all at once all the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the start of 2023 there was a meme AI video of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vbWe5k4fFWE&quot;&gt;Will Smith eating spaghetti&lt;/a&gt; - sorry I can’t find a version of only the 2023 AI video without the 2024 real Will Smith parody of it. But it was terible and the stuff of nightmares. This was created in 2023 using bleeding edge technology at the time! And that was the worst it will ever be. Now we can generate videos so well that it is hard to tell generated videos from reality except for some subtle tells. In time the tells, too, will go away. Leaving no trace of what is reality and what is generated video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Describing a scene made it difficult to generate exactly what you were imagining. Enter Img2Img allowing you to guide the diffusion model into where you wanted things placed by vaguely drawing them for the AI. AI videos suffered from it being difficult to pose a character exactly as you wanted. Enter ControlNet and OpenPose. AI videos suffered from it being difficult to generate a consistent looking character - especially in videos - causing aspects of the character to change from frame to frame. Enter different diffusion denoising techniques to allow better stability. Similar techniques are being applied to backgrounds to make backgrounds more consistent between frames as well. An object in motion was difficult because the motion didn’t seem genuine. I won’t pretend to be smart enough to understand exactly how trajectory was solved but they’ve solved that problem too &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/research/project/dragnuwa/&quot;&gt;with tools like DragNUWA&lt;/a&gt;.I have to remind myself that all of this is bleeding-edge technology and the worst it will ever be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I see things being created that absolutely blow me away and the rate at which I see new mindblowing things is increasing. It used to be years apart I’d stumble across some amazing thing on Github’s trending tab. Then it became every few months. We’re now at the rate that I’m discovering mindblowing, bleeding-edge breakthrough technology every few weeks! The rate of growth is insane and it doesn’t appear that it will be stopping anytime soon. I still can’t believe that ChatGPT isn’t even 2 years old yet - it’s second birthday is in November. There are already short stories and videos being created by humans using entire AI toolchains and workflows. The quality is still bad but is miles over what an individual person could ever hope to accomplish in the timeframe that these things are being made. An animation that would have taken a single person several years to animate can now be done in a few weeks with an “acceptable-enough” result. I cannot wait to see where this technology will be in a few more years! The things people will be creating now that they have the power to create anything they can imagine in almost no time at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until the bubble pops and the money disappears - I do not see the current trend slowing down anytime soon. Even when the bubble pops it doesn’t mean improvements won’t keep getting made (the .com bubble didn’t freeze all internet progress back in the early 2000’s). The curve is no longer linear growth but exponential growth. Either the creation of an artifical general intelligence is truly impossible or it will happen within my lifetime. I’m not so hopeful as to think it will be within a few years or even within the next decade - despite what the marketers for AI companies want people to think - but fuck me if it isn’t seeming more and more likely that it will happen within my lifetime and probably before I have any grandchildren.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every passing day the technologies making all of this possible get a little bit better and single every day continues to be the worst it will ever be.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Luddites</title>
      <link>https://nadyanay.me/blog/blog/articles/2024-18-September/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://nadyanay.me/blog/blog/articles/2024-18-September/</guid>
      <author>Nadya Nayme</author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It feels like I’m living through 2004-2008 all over again. People who can’t think far into the future or have tiny imaginations…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2004 I got my first camera. A point and shoot &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kodak_EasyShare_DX4530&quot;&gt;Kodak EasyShare X4530&lt;/a&gt; gifted to me by my grandmother for Christmas. It wasn’t yet common for every teenager to have a camera that they would carry with them at all times. I’d help take photos of my friends to update their MySpace with. Many of them using particularly poor cameras built into the clamshell-style flip phones of the day. (2004 was probably around peak RAZR popularity but most people had cheaper phone models). I’d take photos of everyday, mundane objects and I wasn’t what you would describe as a “photographer”. I took pictures of things that interested me and what interested me most was using a low shutter speed. I never really got much flack for this offline - people thought my camera was cool! Some of my photography was even described as “good” by people other than my mother. Photography had been an art form for nearly a century and a half.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But not online. Oh no - definitely not yet online. I would be called a wanna-be artist who could only take photos of things because I could not draw them or imagine them. I lacked any skill or talent and that photography was not “real” art. That I should stop cluttering deviantArt with photography. I remember around this time that cracked versions of Photoshop 7 (and later CS1/CS2) were rampant. People were using Photoshop to make digital art and among all that digital art were photo collages and highly edited photos. Of course - digital art wasn’t real art either. Real art required real paper and you could not simply “Ctrl+Z” to undo your mistakes. Digital artists, like photographers, were not taken very seriously in online art communities. Even as digital art became better and better and the things people made more and more amazing - digital art was not real art.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until one day - it was. I’m not exactly sure when this transition took place. I think it is when Wacom tablets were finally cheap enough for hobbyists to start drawing with a “digital pen” and suddenly the medium began receiving more respect. Respect that it had always deserved but was never given. Photoshop was merely a tool, digital art a medium, and artists would create wonderful, creative works with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of that was 20 years ago. And the debates over AI art - even using AI as part of your toolchain - have seemingly come full circle. The barrier to create has been lowered to such that anyone with a bit of spare time and the capability of writing English sentences can have anything they can imagine be created and at a relatively “good” level. Do I think the very first thing generated by a prompt is “art”? Not quite. But curation is an art form and if someone spend shours curating “AI slop” until they find a diamond in the rough - is that diamond not considered art at that point? People are creating image collages using AI-generated art, digital posters, touching up their “hand-made” art. I use quotes around “hand-made” because is digital art “hand-made” now? It wasn’t when I was growing up. I’ve seen tons of AI slop and I’ve seen equally as much AI art. Artists who are incorporating AI as just another tool on their toolbelt to create amazing things that inspire other humans. But I’ve also seen countless people decry that “AI slop isn’t real art” who would be betrayed by their Twitter likes being public - at least before Elon Musk removed that functionality and helped anti-AI luddites from outing themselves as likers of AI art.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it feels like I’m living through 2004-2008 all over again. Ironically a ton of digital art around 2004-2008 was created using stolen things. Stolen photographs (being justified by “if you didn’t want people to steal it don’t post it online where people can ‘right click-&amp;gt;save as’”), stolen IP (anime renders from PlanetRenders.net), pirated copies of Photoshop, uncredited assets and PS brushes. And these same thieves who had turned their early-age piracy into their modern-day careers have the gal to complain about AI “stealing” from them (ignoring that training an AI isn’t &lt;em&gt;fundamentally&lt;/em&gt; too different from artists learning from so called “studies” where they steal and copy from artists they like).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put me in statis and let me wake up in 5-10 years when AI has become “just another tool” like Photoshop already. I’ve dealt with the luddites once already - I did not think I’d have to deal with them twice in a single lifetime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I’ll admit that my memory isn’t perfect. This was over 20 years ago and I was still living life as a child. I wasn’t terminolly online (at least not yet). I had only been around on the internet for a few years. Maybe there were large photography communities online that I simply hadn’t heard of or wasn’t a part of. I believe around this time many photographers were on Flickr as it was the new hot thing. Never caught my attention then.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Get Good</title>
      <link>https://nadyanay.me/blog/blog/articles/2024-05-September/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://nadyanay.me/blog/blog/articles/2024-05-September/</guid>
      <author>Nadya Nayme</author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A growing number of people have forgotten how to learn and have given up on trying. People who are otherwise of at least average intelligence and have no physical disabilities. It’s unfuriating. You “can’t” do something? Bullshit. You’re lazy at best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve started seeing this in various gaming communities. Any level of difficulty harder than walking and chewing bubblegum at the same time has been deemed “inaccessible” or “impossible to learn”. “Easy Mode” is “not easy enough” and people demand a “Story Mode” where the player is essentially an unkillable god with infinite HP or damage given and taken has been tweaked so much that the only way to possibly die would be to put the controller down and go AFK for 20 minutes until the NPCs finally whittle down your hitpoints and kill you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When pressed for their reasons it always comes down to “It’s too hard for me” or “I don’t have enough time.”. The former is what is most people call a “skill issue” and the latter isn’t a good excuse. You cannot get good at something without time. If your time is limited that only means that it will take you longer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not every challenging thing needs to be made accessible. The challenge is a large part of the appeal! If you make a challenge something that anyone is capable of doing it ceases to be a challenge and becomes another checkbox for people to tick off their list. Nobody flexes that they can mentally solve 2*2. However flexing you can quickly solve any 3 digit number multiplied by any other 3 digit number in your head very quickly becomes quite impressive! A great party trick to bust out once in a while too! The difficulty and lack of people who are capable of doing that are what make it so impressive. Nobody is impressed if you can solve 2*2 in your head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a video game is too hard - try practicing it instead of playing it. If you don’t want to practice because video games are meant to be fun - please remember that challenges are supposed to be challenging. Focus your efforts on a challenge you find fun instead of asking for a difficult challenge to be made easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that this is not an attack against accessibility in video games. Color-blind modes are great. High contrast modes are great. Alternative control schemes are great. Varying levels of difficulty are fine. Challenges naturally becoming easier over time due to powercreep is also fine - as the challenge equally loses the prestige it once held over time as it is made easier. Clearing something Day 1 will always be more impressive than clearing it on Day 1000. That is fine and the natural progression of many games. Even games that do not get changed over time can have better strategies developed that make challenges easier to complete or execute. But a challenge being difficult Day 1 is never a good excuse to ask it to be nerfed and made easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead - maybe you should “Get good.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On The Small Web</title>
      <link>https://nadyanay.me/blog/blog/articles/2024-26-August/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26  Aug 2024 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://nadyanay.me/blog/blog/articles/2024-26-August/</guid>
      <author>Nadya Nayme</author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“The Internet” today is as large as it has ever been. It is also as small as it will ever be. Yet it feels as if it is getting smaller as more and more things become centralized. I miss the magic and closer knit communities of the earlier era. I miss “The Small Web”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I consider myself a Netizen. By that I mean I have been surfing online for about as long as I can remember. From times well before Loss or Pepe the Frog; before Rickrolling or the creation of MySpace. Not quite so old as to fondly remember bulletin boards but old enough to know the dial-up tone by heart. I remember an internet without 4chan, without Wikipedia, without Google. No Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, Reddit, Twitch, Tumblr, or YouTube. When you were a single popular GameFAQs Guide away from becoming a second generation e-celeb and video game speedrunning records worked entirely off of a trust system because sharing videos was still too difficult. You just heard about this awesome game on Miniclip called RuneScape and decided to start playing it at the public library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The late 90’s to me were the days of GeoCities, personal websites, and “random” websites. Everything that now has its own subreddit once had its own forum (well - dozens of forums actually). Each forum had its own niche communities. Communities were still small enough that all of the regulars would know one another by name or by avatar. You’d discover new communities because you saw a 88x31 .gif advertising the website on someone’s blogring. Photoshop pirates would practice by creating you a “sig” or a “tag”. You’d see a geek code in the wild and understand it without having to cross-reference everything. GED/J d– s:++&amp;gt;: a– C++(++++) ULU++ P+ L++ E—- W+(-) N+++ o+ K+++ w— O- M+ V– PS++&amp;gt;$ PE++&amp;gt;$ Y++ PGP++ t- 5+++ X++ R+++&amp;gt;$ tv+ b+ DI+++ D+++ G+++++ e++ h r– y++**. Yeah, remember any of that? Sure you do, Boomer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a unique fondness for the 90s. When the whole world started becoming connected. Instant communication. Worldwide. How beautiful is it that so many countries cooperate to keep something like that working? Your great grandparents could not have imagined a world where you could communicate with someone on the other side of the world in a matter of seconds. That even in countries that try to avoid being connected with the Internet at large still have tunnels where data creeps in and out? Where you were told to be home before dark or call from a friend’s landline and now Mom can track your location live via your cellphone and call you no matter where you are? Memories are divided into two distinct periods: “Before Technology” and “After Technology”. A time when the average person didn’t have the entirity of mankind’s knowledge in a small device carried in their back pocket. Name a more empowering invention than a modern smartphone with an internet connection. I bet you can’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The internet in the early 00’s felt magical. Every now and again I stumble across something that reminds me of that magic but I really have to go looking for it where as it was once seemingly impossible to avoid. “The Algorithm” does not promote such content as often anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are a creator who creates something that you would describe as being a part of “the small web” &lt;a href=&quot;https://nadyanay.me/identities&quot;&gt;please reach out&lt;/a&gt; and show me what you’ve made. I’d love to see it and maybe ask you some questions about it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Keeping up with the (J)one(S).</title>
      <link>https://nadyanay.me/blog/blog/articles/2021-08-May/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://nadyanay.me/blog/blog/articles/2021-08-May/</guid>
      <author>Nadya Nayme</author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve recently decided to update my personal website after it has sat without change for nearly three years. In the process I’ve discovered that if you are not constantly on top of keeping the underlying technologies up-to-date that you are almost better off burning everything to the ground and starting from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to remove Gulp as a build dependency, so I looked at the modern “winners” in this area such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://webpack.js.org/&quot; rel=&quot;external noreferrer&quot;&gt;WebPack&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://parceljs.org/&quot; rel=&quot;external noreferrer&quot;&gt;Parcel&lt;/a&gt; and even trying to use &lt;code&gt;NPM scripts&lt;/code&gt; as a replacement. Maybe I didn’t read the documentation for WebPack and Parcel closely enough but I couldn’t get either to do what I needed it to do and the setup and configuration needed was far more complex than Gulp for my needs. The tools seem designed more in mind for JS Framework SPA’s than they are for braindead asset generating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so I went back to Gulp… Though I am no longer running Node V10 and am using Node V16 and Node V12 introduced a bunch of breaking changes apparently as any up-to-date package requires Node V12+ and Gulp also changed quite a bit going from V3 to V4 and some fo the packages I used were no longer maintained and the list goes on and on. With a bit of Googling around for packages I found the tools I needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I decide I wanted a blog. But to easily manage a blog I needed a static-site generator. But I also need this generator to be unobtrusive with my existing build setup. I’ve used &lt;a href=&quot;https://hexo.io/&quot; rel=&quot;external noreferrer&quot;&gt;Hexo.io&lt;/a&gt; a while back for some work-related things. I may end up going back to it for the benefit of blog categories and tags but Hexo setup is a lot more involved than I wanted to get my blog up and running. In the end I went with &lt;a href=&quot;http://wintersmith.io/&quot; rel=&quot;external noreferrer&quot;&gt;Wintersmith.io&lt;/a&gt;. With almost no configuration needed this blog was up-and-running.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hello world! From cute-laptop</title>
      <link>https://nadyanay.me/blog/blog/articles/2023-06-July/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://nadyanay.me/blog/blog/articles/2023-06-July/</guid>
      <author>Nadya Nayme</author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve recently decided to update my personal website after it has sat without change for nearly three years. In the process I’ve discovered that if you are not constantly on top of keeping the underlying technologies up-to-date that you are almost better off burning everything to the ground and starting from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After over 460 days of not being used - I’ve finally busted out the old X60 Thinkpad again and got it up and running again. The goal of the laptop was a safe place to learn Linux. I never exactly got around to doing that and the laptop has gathered dust for closer to 2-3 years with only the occasional dusting off and &lt;code&gt;sudo pacman -Syu&lt;/code&gt; being ran. The laptop has once again been dusted off and to encourage myself to actually go through with learning Linux this time I decided to get my website build system up and running on the laptop. &lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt; This should allow me to write blogs from the laptop and have the build go directly to webdav. Until I’m certain I’ve set things up right I’m going to rely on &lt;code&gt;mv&lt;/code&gt; but the goal is to eventually be in a place where I can &lt;code&gt;touch&lt;/code&gt; a new blog post and publish it&lt;span class=&quot;widont&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;easily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t have much to say here other than “I’ll finally be blogging like I planned&lt;span class=&quot;widont&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;to”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assuming building this blog works out - I expect to start immediately on something I’ve wanted to blog about for a while. Which is what the retro/small web means to&lt;span class=&quot;widont&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>